# MOHAMMAD BAHMANI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **SUMMARY**

As an exprienced software developer with over 2 years of exprience, I posses s deep understanding Of software development life cycle, agile methodologies and programming languages such as JavaScript, Java, Python and frameworks like Express.js, React.js and Tailwind CSS. My expertise lies In designing and devloping scalable, efficient, and secure software solution for clients across Various industries. Additionally I am a proactive team player who is committed to continuous Learning and staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies.

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

1/2023 - present

#### Web Developer and Web Development Instructor

iTex Services

- Develop and maintain web-based application using Mern Stack (MongoDB, Express js, React js and node js.
- Collaborate with cross functional teams to design and implement software solutions that meet the client requirement.
- Document and test old and new software applications.
- Optimize application performance and ensecure robustness and security.
- Write clean, maintainable, and efficient code that adhere to industry standards.
- Troubleshoot and debug software issues to ensure optional performance.

2/2020 - 12/2022

#### Front-end developer

Setaragan-e-Tamadon Private High School

- Design and Develop responsive web application using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React and Tailwind CSS.
- Implement scalable and high-performance front-end architecture and infrastructure.
- Develop and maintain front-end systems and user interface using JavaScript and JavaScript Frameworks.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to ensure timely deliver of projects.
- Stayed up to date with latest trends and technologies in front end development to ensure continuous improvement of skills and knowledge.

7/2019 - 1/2020

#### **Social Marketer and Website Adminstrator**

Roydad-roz News Agency

- Develop and execute social media campaigns across various platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and news agency website.
- Manage Website content using control panels and cpanel.
- Create engaging and relevent content for social media channels including graphics, videos And written content.
- Develop and maintain website documentation including user guides and training Materials.
- collaborate with cross functional teams including marketing, design, development and sales to ensure social media compaigns align with overall marketing strategy.

### CONTACT\_



Shaheed Mazari street, Kabul, Afghanistan



+93778990838



mohammadmandegar 2019@gmail.com @mandegar 363

### **SKILLS**



# LANGUAGE\_



# **EDUCATION**\_

### Information Technology

Kabul University 2019-2023

### **High School**

Setaragan-e-Tamadon Private High School 2008-2018

# **REFERENCE**\_

### **Ghulam Rasool Mustafavy**

Network Engineer | Afghan Telecom ghulam.mustafavy@gmail.com | +93788874641

#### Mohammad Essa Rahemi

Network Engineer | 3D Systems essa.rahemi@3dsystems.com | +32466477562

### Ali Mohammad Aliyar

Senior Associate | Acasus - Brave Change alialiyar@gmail.com | +93773102919

## **INTERESTS**

- Photography
- Coding
- Poem
- Soccer